# Dhanya Venkatesh

## Product / UI/UX Designer

Portfolio link: https://www.behance.net/dhanyasada06a5

### +61 426773439

dhanya.sada@gmail.com

### Savvy With

#### Software

Adobe Creative Suite

Microsoft office suite

Adobe XD

Sketch

Axure & Invision

#### PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Master's degree in Interactive Design from the Griffith University of Australia.

Talented UI and UX Designer with more than 4 years of work experience.

Skilled with Adobe Creative Suite, Microsoft Office and web design (CSS, HTML), Final cut pro, Autodesk, Axure RP, Invision, Adobe XD, etc

Proven ability to work creatively and analytically in a problem-solving environment.

Enthusiastic entry-level Scrum Master. Have worked in an Agile environment as a UX Designer

#### **EDUCATION**

Griffith University, Brisbane. Master's in interactive Media, Dec 2017

- Designed a web-based storytelling application from wireframes and delivered the final design in production quality as part of a master's project.
- Extensively worked with Adobe Creative Suite to design all the web pages for the above-mentioned project.
- Involved in researching a product from a user experience point to provide a more efficient user experience.
- Created Branding for many products as apart of my coursework using Adobe Creative Suite and Sketch.

Wiztoonz College of Media and Design. Bangalore Bachelor's in Multimedia, June 2013

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

OSE, Brisbane, Australia Digital Agency

UX Designer, October 2018- Present

Tools Used: Adobe Creative suite, XD, Invision.

- Consultation with management, clients and developers on UX screen designs
- Overseeing projects from gathering analysis, through to user centric- design with a strong knowledge of user experience design
- Responsible for clearing obstacles to ensure clear communication between the product owner and the team to ensure to follow proper Agile.

Unikrn Pty ltd, Brisbane, Australia Blockchain and esports betting entrepreneur

UI/UX Designer, May 2018- August 2018

Tools Used: Adobe Creative suite, Sketch, Invision.

- Responsible for collaborating with developers and project managers to design successful User Experiences.
- Responsible for the illustration of UX ideas and translate them to user flows, wireframes, mockups, and prototypes that lead to intuitive user experiences
- Work closely with the Head of Data and the Head of Product to evaluate user requirements
- Evaluating competitors and best practice design for UX based on market research and conducting regular testing of UX solutions
- As a Scrum Master, I ensure that the team follows agile values and principles.
- Also, my responsibilities include clearing obstacles to ensure clear communication between the product owner
  and the team for conducting proper scrum ceremonies to plan the work ahead of us properly.

Keara Education, Brisbane, Australia

A Student service center.

UI Design, March 2017- April 2018

Tools Used: Adobe Creative suite.

- Branding and Creating Advertisements for International students.
- Designed wireframes for mobile and web application.
- Researched areas where students needed the most assistance and designed advertisements based on information gathered.

Webacadabra Pvt Ltd, Bangalore, India

A B2B marketing firm.

Consultant UI/UX Designer, July 2014 – Sep 2015

Tools Used: Adobe Creative suite, HTML, CSS, Apple Final Cut Pro X

Key achievement: Designed a timesheet which is used companywide to track employee working hours.

- Involved in the design, development, and implementation of the graphic, layout, and production communication for mobile and web application.
- Interpreted the client's business needs and developed a concept of wireframes to suit their purpose.
- Developed design briefs by gathering information and data through research
- Worked with the UX team in an architectural change of the IoT Cloud product. Worked closely with PM's and
  Designers to redefine the rule builder experience, Through rapid research and iterative wireframes, crafted pixel
  sharp concepts within given constraints..
- Developing Information architecture, interactive design and character for wireframes.

Ad2pro Pvt Ltd, Bangalore, India

A full-service ad agency

Graphic Designer, July 2013- July 2014

Tools Used: Adobe Creative suite, Photography

- Developed numerous marketing programs including logos, brochures, newsletters, infographics, presentations, and advertisements.
- Worked for Fairfax, Australia for creating print ads and web banner ads.
- Thorough understanding of digital technologies and trends.
- Working with a wide range of media, including photography.

Focus Eduvation, Bangalore, India

A full-service ad agency and eLearning company creating study materials.

Graphic Designer, January 2013- June 2013

Tools Used: Adobe Creative suite

- Involved in creating user experience and template designing.
- Acitively involved in the usability testing.
- Designed canvas based games and complex animations for e-learning